- ♪ D-o-r-a
♪ Dora and friends
into the city ♪
♪ Tall buildings,
so much more ♪
♪ An adventure
behind each door ♪
- ¡Vámanos!
- ♪ Come on, let's explore
♪ Con todos mis amigos
♪ Make a difference,
take a chance ♪
- Let's go!
♪ Come and lend
a helping hand ♪
♪ Hold on tight
♪ Canta conmigo
♪ Dora, Dora
and friends ♪
♪ Goin' into the city,
goin' into the city ♪
♪ Todos juntos
♪ D-o-r-a
♪ Dora and friends
into the city ♪
♪ D-o-r-a
- Dora!
- ♪ Adventure every day
- Bienvenidos, amigos.
- ¡Hola!
- Clap with us.
- BOTH: [clapping]
- ♪ Hola, hola, hola
♪ Bienvenidos
♪ We're so very,
very happy to see you ♪
♪ Soy Dora
♪ Y yo soy Kate
♪ We're trying on costumes
from our treasure chest ♪
- What are we dressed up as?
- BOTH: Pirates!
- Right, mateys.
- Arrrg!
- We're at a pirate festival
with games.
- And lots of cool
pirate stuff.
- The best part is we're helping
mi mami raise money
to turn this old fort
into a museum.
- Sí, we're selling tickets
for a pirate ship ride.
- Dora is going to take
everybody out on the sea
and you'll come
with us, right?
- BOTH: Awesome!
- ♪ Helping out
in the city ♪
♪ Doing what we can
♪ We do our best
with help from you ♪
♪ So, hola, hola, hola
hola, hola, hola ♪
♪ Hola, hola, hola
Bienvenidos, yeah ♪
- Achoo!
I love this stuff, but sometimes
it makes me sneeze.
Ah...ah...achoo!
- BOTH: Salud, Pablo.
- Gracias.
Wow, you guys look great.
Can I help out?
- DORA & KATE: Sure.
- But, first, you need
to do one important thing.
- What's that?
- DORA & KATE: Be a pirate!
- ♪
- ALL: [laughing]
- Is Pablo dressed up
as a pirate?
- No. What is he
dressed up as?
A penguin!
- DORA & KATE: [laughing]
- Now what's Pablo
dressed up as?
- DORA & KATE: A banana?
[laughing]
- Ha! Ha!
- Pablo.
- Perfecto, Pablo.
Now you look like
a real pirate.
- Yo! Ho! Ho!
- Hey, let's all
be pirates, when I sing...
♪ Be a pirate
You sing...
♪ Yo Ho Ho
♪ Be a pirate
♪ Adventure waits
so let's get going ♪
♪ Any way
the wind is blowing ♪
♪ Be a pirate
♪ Yo Ho Ho
♪ It's a pirate festival
♪ And I'm here with
all me mates ♪
♪ Ahoy!
♪ To help the new museum
let's all celebrate ♪
♪ Arrrg!
♪ We're putting
out the call ♪
♪ To pirates
one and all ♪
♪ Come and sail
the ocean blue ♪
♪ Be one of our crew
♪ Be a pirate
♪ Yo Ho Ho
- Look, all our friends
are helping out.
Kate's making
pirate balloons.
- Naiya's at
the telescope.
- Alana's running
a pirate net climb.
- And what's Emma doing?
Right, painting
pirate faces.
Achoo!
- When Pablo sneezes,
we say salud, Pablo.
Say salud, Pablo.
- Gracias.
- ♪ Be a pirate
♪ Yo Ho Ho
♪ Be a pirate
♪ Adventure waits
so let's get going ♪
♪ Any way
the wind is blowing ♪
♪ Be a pirate
♪ Yo Ho Ho
- Disculpa,
are you the captain
of the pirate ship?
- Yeah, I'm Dora.
- I'm Jorge.
Mi mami is buying me
a ticket for the pirate ride.
I can't wait.
- That's great, Jorge.
Buying a ticket is helping
us open the museum.
Do you like museums?
- I guess.
- Oh, you'll love this one.
It'll have lots of
cool stuff
from when this place
was a fort.
- Ooh, will there be
pirate stuff?
- Claro, por supuesto.
- Awesome!
I love learning about pirates.
- Great.
Hey, how about I let you
steer the ship?
- Ooh, I'd love that.
Promise?
- I promise.
- BOTH: [palm slap]
- ♪
- Um, where's the pirate
ship, anyway?
- It should be down
by the dock. Come on.
- ♪
- Uh-oh, the pirate
ship isn't here.
- Maybe it's late?
- Ay, mijita.
There's bad news.
The pirate ship we rented for
the festival isn't coming.
- But we need
the pirate ship
to make enough money
for the museum.
- Oh, and I promised Jorge
that he could steer.
I have to keep my promise.
- But how are you gonna
take a pirate ship ride,
if there's no pirate ship?
- I've got it.
That rowboat.
- Uh, Dora...
I don't see people buying
tickets for a rowboat ride.
- Well, it's just
a rowboat now,
but what if we turned
it into...
our own pirate ship?
- Great idea, D.
- Yeah, and I bet we can find
some pirate stuff
in the museum basement.
Can we look, Mommy?
- Claro que sí.
- Vamos, amigos.
- KIDS: Let's make
a pirate ship!
- ♪
♪ What makes
a pirate ship? ♪
♪ Piece by piece
and bit by bit ♪
♪ We're gonna make
this boat brand new ♪
♪ And decorate it, too
♪ What makes
a pirate ship? ♪
♪ Before we take off
on our ocean trip ♪
♪ We're gonna make
this boat brand new ♪
♪ And decorate it, too
♪ But we need
some help from you ♪
- What do we need to make
our pirate ship go?
Sails. Right.
If you see any sails,
yell "Sails!"
- Sails!
- Cool!
- ♪ What makes
a pirate ship? ♪
♪ Piece by piece
and bit by bit ♪
♪ We're gonna make
this boat brand new ♪
♪ And decorate it, too
- Now what else
do we need for the ship?
A flag, correcto.
A pirate flag.
If you see one,
yell "Flag!"
- Flag! Wahoo!
- ♪ What makes
a pirate ship? ♪
♪ Piece by piece
and bit by bit ♪
♪ We're gonna make
this boat brand new ♪
♪ And decorate it, too
- We need one more thing.
What is it?
Right. A wheel.
Can you see a wheel?
- Yeah, there it is.
We've found it.
- Yo Ho Ho!
- ♪ What makes
a pirate ship? ♪
♪ Piece by piece
and bit by bit ♪
♪ We're gonna make
this boat brand new ♪
♪ And we'll decorate
it, too ♪
♪
- This wheel is stuck.
Can't spin it.
I've just gotta...
One, two, three!
Whoa!
Something's happening.
Whoa! Whoa!
Ahhhhh!
- Pablo, that wheel's
enchanted.
- Hey, wheel, you can't
just pull me around
wherever you want.
Whoa!
I guess you can.
Wahoo!
- Be careful, Pablo.
- Wheee!
- Hang on.
- DORA & PABLO: Whoa!
- Dora! Pablo!
- Come on and
find us, Kate.
- I will.
And remember
to turn the wheel.
- DORA & PABLO: Okay!
- ♪ It's fast, it glows
♪ And who knows
where it goes ♪
♪ It's quick, unreal
♪ And we've gotta
turn the wheel ♪
♪ Yeah we've gotta
- Whoa, there are
booby traps.
We've got to turn the wheel
around those nets.
- DORA & PABLO:
[groaning]
- We need help.
- Can you help us
turn the wheel?
Muy bien.
Put your hands out in
front of you like this.
- Hold on to the wheel.
Perfecto.
Now the net.
- DORA & PABLO: Turn!
Turn! Turn! Turn!
- Yeah, we got around
the net.
♪ We've gotta
turn the wheel ♪
♪ Yeah turn the wheel
♪ We're not joking,
it's for real ♪
♪ We've gotta
turn the wheel ♪
- Water spray.
I don't wanna get wet.
- Well, I don't, either.
- Turn the wheel!
- Come on, let's turn
the wheel around the water.
- DORA & PABLO: Turn!
Turn! Turn! Turn!
- Awesome. We got
past the water.
- Thanks!
- ♪ We don't know
where it's going ♪
♪ We're racing
down the path ♪
♪ There's no chance
that it's slowing ♪
♪ We've gotta
turn real fast ♪
- Whoa!
Flying buoys?
- Turn the wheel
around them.
- DORA & PABLO: Turn!
Turn! Turn! Turn!
- Wahoo!
- ♪ We turned
the wheel, yeah ♪
♪ Turned the wheel
♪ With your help
we turned the wheel ♪
- Yay, we got past
the traps.
Thanks for helping.
- Great turning.
- ♪
- Look, a real
pirate ship.
- ♪
- Whoa.
- Capitana Malencua,
usted ha regresado.
You've returned!
- Lo siento, pirate ship.
I'm not your
pirate captain.
Soy Dora.
- And I'm Pablo.
Who's Capitana Malencua?
- Oh, she was my captain
a long time ago.
- Was she a pirate?
- Oh, yes.
But a very good pirate.
Let me tell you about her.
- ♪
♪ Malencua was a pirate,
a very good pirate ♪
♪ And by that I mean
a pirate who was good ♪
♪ And kind and nice
♪ She helped the people
who lived there ♪
♪ And she showed them
that she cared ♪
♪ And protected them
as best as she could ♪
♪ When mean
and nasty pirates ♪
♪ Took the people's
treasure away ♪
♪ Malencua would go
after it ♪
♪ And made
the pirates pay ♪
♪ She had a magic
charm bracelet ♪
♪ That she used
to cast a spell ♪
- Alcón mágico.
- ♪
♪ And a charm would
grow and help her ♪
♪ And she'd teach
those pirates well ♪
♪ That Malencua
was a pirate ♪
♪ A very good pirate
♪ And by that I mean
a pirate who was good ♪
- Wow, Capitana Malencua
returned the treasure
to the people?
- That's different.
- Oh, yes, and the people
loved mi capitana so much.
- But how did you wind
up in this cave, pirate ship?
- Well, when evil pirates
came after us,
Capitana Malencua kept
the treasure safe
by hiding me in
this cave.
- DORA & PABLO: Treasure?
- Yes, a chest filled
with treasure.
Do you want to see it?
- DORA & PABLO: Yeah!
- Do you want to see
the treasure?
- Maravilloso.
To unlock the treasure,
you must turn the wheel.
- Well, we know how
to do that.
- Put your hands
out in front of you,
grab the wheel,
and turn it.
- DORA & PABLO:
Turn! Turn! Turn!
Whoa!
- Treasure!
- Estupendo.
- MAN: Finally! Huh!
You found it.
- ♪ So long so long
♪ We've been
waiting so long ♪
♪ Waiting for so long
♪ To get the treasure chest
- My great-great grandfather
tried to get this treasure.
And now, finally,
it's mine! Mine! Mine!
- PIRATES: [humming]
♪ So long so long
♪ We've been
waiting so long ♪
♪ Finally we've got
Malencua's treasure chest ♪
- SHIP: Oh, no.
- The pirates got
the treasure chest.
- We've got to
get it back.
- But how are we
gonna do that, Dora?
We don't have a magic
charm bracelet.
- SHIP: But you do.
- DORA & PABLO: [gasp]
- SHIP: Look on
the steering wheel.
- DORA: Do you see
a charm bracelet?
There it is.
- SHIP: Put it on, Dora.
Malencua wanted the one
who tried to save me
to have her
magic bracelet.
- ♪
- SHIP: Look at all
the bracelet's charms
and choose the one that will
scare the pirates.
- DORA: Will a telescope
scare the pirates?
No. Do you see something
that will scare the pirates?
Right. The sea serpent.
La serpiente.
To get the sea serpent
to appear, we need to say...
serpiente mágica.
Can you say
Excelente.
Say it with me.
Serpiente mágica.
- Louder!
Serpiente mágica!
- ♪
- DORA: It worked!
- Let's help the sea serpent
scare the pirates.
Say "Roar!".
- [serpent roars]
- Louder!
- [roaring louder]
- Take the treasure.
Take the treasure.
Ahhhh!
- The sea serpent's got
the treasure chest.
- SHIP: And he's
bringing it back.
- Now we've gotta
get out of here.
- But we have no sails.
- I've got those.
- Mira.
It's Kate.
- Here you go, mateys.
- Hurray!
- All right!
You did it, Kate.
- Help us hoist the sails.
- Put your hands out
in front of you.
- Grab a line and...
- ALL: Pull! Pull! Pull!
- It worked!
- Great pulling.
- All right!
- [balloon pops]
- [sea serpent gasps]
- Hey, where's la serpiente?
- He ducked under
the water?
- How come?
- He was scared?
- Oh, it must have been
when my balloon popped.
Oh, pobrecita serpiente.
- [cannonball fires]
- [sea serpent gasps]
- Hey, ha, ha, ha.
That sea serpent is afraid
of loud noises.
He can't protect you.
Now give me back
the treasure.
- Let's get out of here.
- ♪
- Look, three ways out.
- We need to find the fastest
way out of the cave.
- Map App will get us
out of here fast.
Say "Map App."
- ♪ I'll get you
where you want to go ♪
♪ I'm Map App, Map App
Ooh, Dora needs to get
out of the cave fast.
Well, I can find
the fastest way.
There are three ways
to get out of the cave.
Is the shortest one to the left,
straight ahead, or to the right?
Correct. Tell Dora
to go straight ahead.
- Go straight ahead?
Awesome! Thanks!
We're heading
straight, mateys.
- KATE & PABLO: Aye-aye,
Captain Dora.
- ♪
- Hey, the pirates
are still following us.
- That's okay, Pablo.
We're nearly out of here.
- ♪
- KATE: Uh-oh, they're firing
their cannon.
- ♪
- Yikes, the cannonball
hit the wall.
- And the wall is closing.
- We've gotta go faster.
- But we need more wind.
- Achoo!
- KATE & DORA:
Salud, Pablo.
- Pablo, really?
Now you're taking a snack break?
- I can't help it.
I love this stuff.
- Wait--that's it.
- What? We should take a break?
But what about the pirates?
- No, Pablo, your sneeze--
it's like a wind.
- And we need
a really big wind.
- So, who do we know
who's really big?
- ALL: Serpiente.
- Pablo, get ready to
throw peppercorns
at la serpiente to make
him sneeze.
- Aye-aye, Capitana.
- When you see the sea serpent,
say serpiente.
- ALL: Serpiente!
- There he is.
- [chomping]
[gulps]
Ah...ah...ah...
Achooooooo!
- ♪
- Say salud, serpiente.
Ven, serpiente.
- ALL: Wheee!
- ♪
- We made it out
and the treasure is safe.
- And we've got an awesome
pirate ship to sail.
- I can keep
my promise to Jorge.
- ALL: Wahoo!
- But, look!
Everyone is leaving
the festival.
- They think there's
no pirate ride.
We have to let them know
we've got a pirate ship.
- Help us call
to the people.
Say "Yo! Ho! Ho!"
- ALL: Louder!
Yo! Ho! Ho!
- CROWD: [cheering]
- The ship is coming!
- They heard us.
And all the families
are coming back
to buy tickets for
the pirate ship ride.
- Thank you for helping us
restore the museum.
- CROWD: [cheering]
- Todos abordo.
- Come on, amigos.
Let's go out for
a pirate ride.
- ALL: Yo! Ho! Ho!
- We got a pirate ship
for the pirate festival.
- And raised enough money
for the museum.
Now all the kids
can get a ride.
- And I can keep
my promise to Jorge.
- ALL: [cheering]
- ♪
♪ And we couldn't have
done it without you ♪
♪ Todos juntos
- Clap with us.
- Hey! Hey! Hey!
♪ Together,
all for one ♪
♪ That's how
we got it done ♪
♪ We helped
out everyone ♪
♪ All for one
♪ We found lost treasure
when we turned the wheel ♪
♪ All for one
♪ And stopped the pirates
when they tried to steal ♪
♪ All for one
♪ We saved the festival
with you on our side ♪
♪ All for one
♪ Everyone's on board
for a pirate ship ride ♪
- And I get to steer!
♪ 'Cause we couldn't have
done it without you ♪
♪ Todfos juntos
- Hey! Hey! Hey!
- ♪ Together,
all for one ♪
♪ That's how
we got it done ♪
♪ We helped
out everyone ♪
♪ All for one
♪
- We had such a great
adventure today.
- Fue increíble.
- Yeah, pretty awesome.
- Magnífico, niños.
The pirate ship will bring lots
more visitors to the museum
and the treasure will be put
on display for everyone.
- ALL: [palm slap]
- We helped raise money
to turn that old fort
into a beautiful museum.
Would you like to
visit a museum
and learn about pirates?
- Great.
- Awesome.
- Fantástico.
- We're really glad
you helped us today.
- Making a difference
is always an adventure.
- DORA & PABLO: Adios, amigos.
- See you soon!